Simon Flexner Papers 1891-1946 Mss.B.F365
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Simon Flexner Papers, 1891-1946; 115.5 linear feet
  - Woods, Andrew H.
  - Woods, Archie S.
  - Woods, Arthur, 6 folders
  - Woods, Carl
  - Woods, E. B.
  - Woods, Hiram
  - Woodward, Robert S.
  - Woodward, W. C.
  - Woodyatt, R. T.
  - Woolbert, Roy
  - Woolbridge, P.
  - Wooley, D. W.
  - Woolfender, William
  - Woolley, J. Stanley
  - Woolley, Paul G.
  - Woringer, P.
  - Memoranda
  - Wormall, Arthur
  - Wormser, Lucien
  - Worthen, John H.
  - Worthington, Anne
  - Worthington, Grace
  - Worthington, Harold
  - Worthington, Mrs. Valentine
  - Wortman, E.
  - Woughter, Mae L.
  - Wrench, W. W.
  - Wrenn, Alphonse A.
  - Wright, A. E.
  - Wright, Sir Almroth
  - Wright, Arthur
  - Wright, Arthur M.
  - Wright, Arthur W.
  - Wright, Barton L.
  - Wright, Ernest Hunter
  - Wright, Fred E.
  - Wright, H. P.
  - Wright, Henry C.
  - Wright, Irving S.
  - Wright, J. Butler
  - Wright, J. Homer
  - Wright, John F.
  - Wright, Jonathan
  - Wright, Myron W.
  - Wright, R. C.
  - Wright, R. G.
  - Wright, R. R.
  - Wrinch, Dorothy
  - Wuest, Margaret
  - Wurster, Lloyd E.
  - Wurtmann, B. E.
  - Wyatt, Robert E.
  - Wyckoff, Ralph W. G., 1926-1937; 5 folders
    Includes: Letter to SF on duties of Miss Armstrong as assistant to himself and Hendricks in work of X-ray spectroscopy, 4/22/27. Letter to SF giving account of new X-ray tubes being manufactured by Siemens AG Co. in Germany, which could extend scope of biological and crystal structure researches, 7/7/28. Letter to SF on his and John W. Gowen's interest in using ultraviolet microscope to obtain other details of structure of dividing and X-rayed cells, 7/11/30. Brief report of their work with the ultraviolet microscope on chromosome charges occurring in induced mutation by soft X-rays in Drosophila, 10/23/30. Draft of article by Wyckoff, J. Biscoe and W. M. Stanley, "An ultracentrifugal analysis of the crystalline virus proteins isolated from plants diseased with different strains of tobacco mosaic virus," published in Journal of Biological Chemistry. Letter to SF discussing present and future status of biophysics, 9/4/34. 7 pp. Letter to SF reporting he and his co-workers had obtained a sedimented protein in which they were able to detect a definite crystalline protein pattern on X-ray pictures, 2/25/37. General correspondence.
  - Wyeth, John A.
  - Wylie, Rae M.
  - Wyman, Sterling C.
  - Wyman, W.
  - Wyn, Norman B.
  - Wynkoop, Edward J.
  - Wynn, Frank B.
  - Wynn, Laurel Archibald
  - Wynne, Shirley W., 2 folders
  - Wyse, Elizabeth
  - Yaboadas, F.
  - Yada, Chonosuke
  - Yager, J. Allen
  - Yaggi, Henry E.
  - Yakimoff, W. L.
  - Yale Review
  - Yale University
  - Yamagiwa, K.
  - Yamakawa
  - Yamamoto, M. T.
  - Yamanaka and Co.
  - Yamanda, M.
  - Yamanouchi
  - Yamazaki, Izne
  - Yandell, Enid
  - Yandell, Maud
  - Yang, Peter S.
  - Yankovitch, Radoye
  - Yates, H.
  - Yates, J. L.
  - Yates, John Carrington
  - Yates, Robert
  - Yates, Thomas M.
  - Yates, William J.
  - Yeager, Edith
  - Yebes, Condesa de
  - Yen, F. C.
  - Yen, U. J.
  - Yerkes, G.
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1916-1931; 3 folders
    Includes: Outline of his plans for study of primates, 1/11/16. Correspondence on NRC's publication on contributions of medicine to WWI, 1919. Correspondence concerning RIMR's supply of a chimpanzee to Yerkes, 1929-1930.
  - Yerle, Henriette
  - Ying, Yang Yu
  - Yocum, A. Duncan
  - Yorkville Record
  - Yoshii, Edward E.
  - Yoshioka, M.
  - Youland, William E.
  - Young, Alice C.
  - Young, Arthur A.
  - Young, C. T.
  - Young, Charles H.
  - Young, Charles W.
  - Young, Hugh H.
  - Young, J. Lowe
  - Young, John R.
  - Young, John Van Doren
  - Young, Martha
  - Young, Muriel
  - Young, R. G.
  - Young, R. T.
  - Young, W. Nelson
  - Youngman, Burt
  - Yourievitch, S.
  - Yuhlan
  - Yust, Walter
  - Zabolotny, D.
  - Zabriskie
  - Zacker, Myron A.
  - Zahn, Charles T., 2 folders
  - Zanetti, J. E.
  - Zanuttini, Candido
  - Zaret, Harry
  - Zaring, E. T.
  - Zehnder, A. Charles
  - Zelle, Oscar L.
  - Zequeira y Rivera, Garbiel de
  - Zerfas, L. G.
  - Ziegler, S. Lewis
  - Ziemann, H.
  - Zilberman, Belle Neuman
  - Zillessen, F. O.
  - Zimmerman
  - Zimmerman, H. M.
  - Zimmermann, Carl A. W.
  - Zingher, Abraham
  - Zinke, Stanley G.
  - Zinn, Earl F.
  - Zinner
  - Zinsser, Carl
  - Zinsser, Hans, 1913-1935; 11 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on supply of gonococcus to RIMR, 1913. Correspondence on Dr. Manwaring's appointment to Stanford University as head of Department of Bacteriology. Administrative correspondence on training of armed service personnel at RIMR, 1917-1918. Correspondence on work of Jacques Bronfenbrenner, 1923. Letters on his appointment as head of Department of Bacteriology and Immunology, Harvard University Medical School, 1923. General correspondence concerning student assistantships at various universities, 1926-1929. Scientific correspondence on his work on herpes encephalitis and poliomyelitis.
  - Zinsser, William H.
  - Zionist Organization of America
  - Zironi, Amilcare
  - Zlatogoroff, S. J.
  - Zozaya, Jose
  - Zucker, Eugen
  - Zucker, F. A.
  - Zunz, Edgard
  - Zwick, W.
  - Zyre, D.
- Series II. Photographs
  All of these images are availble in a gallery. View gallery.
  Native American Images Note: Photographs of Navajo and Tohono O'Odham (Papago) Native Americans from Fort Defiance and Sells, Arizona, taken in 1926 to accompany a field report to the Rockefeller Insitute for Medical Research of an outbreak of trachoma. Taken by an unknown photographer as reported to Frederick F. Russell, board member of the RIMR, the eleven black and white silver gelatin prints show dwellings, a lapidary, and rug weaving. Of note are the patterned blankets worn by the natives standing in front of their hogans. Note: all photographs are housed in the APS Photograph Collection with identifying numbers, U4.4.34; U5.2.136-145.
  - Morris Flexner, [ca. 1856]
  - Navajo Hogan with women and children, 1926; U4.4.34; 4 ½ x 3 ½ inches silver gelatin print
    - Navajo hogan, 1926
  - Papago reservation, dwelling with woman, 1926; U5.2.136; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
    - Tohono O'Odham woman, 1926
  - Papago reservation dwelling, 1926; U5.2.137; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Papago reservation landscape, 1926; U5.2.138; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Papago reservation landscape, 1926; U5.2.139; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Papago reservation family portrait, 1926; U5.2.140; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
    - Tohono O'Odham reservation
  - Papago reservation, Sells agency hospital, 1926; U5.2.141; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Native American woman, blanket weaving, 1926; U5.2.142
    - Tohono O'Odham blanket weaving, 1926
  - Canyon del Muerto, 1926; U5.2.143; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Native American family, with livestock, 1926; U5.2.144; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
  - Papago reservation family portrait, 1926; U5.2.145; 3 ¼ x 5 ½ inches silver gelatin print
    - Tohono O'Odham family, 1926
  - Esther Abraham Flexner, [ca. 1856]
  - Large house, birthplace of Simon Flexner's mother, Esther Abraham, in Roden with eighteen unidentified people in front, 1893
    On Back: "House in which my mother liven in Roden. This photograph taken in 1893 on my visit her birthplace. "S.F. The visit was made in the Easter vacation (?) while I was in laboratories in Strausburg in the spring semester of 1893."
  - Flexner family, ca. 1870
  - Simon Flexner at a young age., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Bust length portrait of Flexner at a young age, name label visible from album page.
  - Simon Flexner, two women, and a man wearing a sombrero and fake mustache in the "El Chico" restaurant in New York City, March 10, 1939
    On mount: "Taken at 'El Chico' Restaurant - Greenwich Village - New York City, Mar. 10, 1939"
  - Harold Amoss, at lab desk with microscope, ca. 1922
  - Simon Flexner and Alexis Carrel, standing in laboratory, ca. 1915
  - Rufus Cole, at laboratory desk holding dropper, ca. 1925-1935
  - William Thomas Councilman, at desk in study smoking pipe, n.d.
    Written on mount: W.T. Councilman in J. H.H. Study (later S. F.study)
  - Albert Einstein, n.d.
  - Elizabeth, Queen of Belgium, visiting the Rockefeller Institute, 1919
  - Family of Frederick Lamont Gates, n.d.
  - Jacques Loeb, standing in doorway
  - Catherine Lotsy and Haas Moeder, 1910
  - Franklin Paine Mall, wearing labcoat, n.d.
  - Frank Mallory, 1928
  - Florentin Medigreceanu, n.d.
    Signed on mount: "With best regards, F. Medigreceanu."
  - Ralph G. Mills, 1924
  - George H. F. Nuttall, in collegiate robe, 1920
    Signed on mount: "To Simon Flexner from his old friend George H. F Nuttall, Cambridge 1920."
  - Winthrop John Banleuven Osterhaut, n.d.
    On mount: "To Dr. Flexner, with kindest regards- W.J.V. Osterhaut"
  - Louis Pasteur, n.d.
  - Walter Reed in uniform, n.d.
  - John D. Rockefeller with boy holding golf clubs, ca. 1935
  - Pierre Paul Emile Roux, at microscope, n.d.
  - Theobald Smith, July 31, 1934
    Written on back: Taken the day after his 75th birthday
  - Karl Sudhoff, n.d.
  - Rudolf Ludwig Carl Virchow, n.d.
  - Almroth Edward Wright and Arnold C. Klebs, June 1928
  - Lewellys F. Barker, Franklin P. Mall, F. R. Smith, Simon Flexner, and William Sydney Thayer; in officer's dining room at Johns Hopkins Hospital, ca. 1895
    Upper half of page containing two photographs
  - Lewellys F. Barker, F. R. Smith, Simon Flexner, and William Sydney Thayer; in Thayer's study at Johns Hopkins Hospital, ca. 1895
    Lower half of page containing two photographs
  - 33 unidentified men and women of the graduate class of Johns Hopkins Medical school, 1898 and 1899, 1898-1899
    Photograph includes Dr.Cushing, Dr. Kelley, Dr. Osler, Dr. William Sydney Thayer
  - Frederick George Novy, Lewellys F. Franklin, and Simon Flexner, 1901
    U.S. Commission to Investigate Plague - San Francisco, 1901
  - 21 men and women, members of the Department of Pathology standing outside Peking University Medical College, 1924
  - Simon Flexner in a group at the first meeting of the Medical Advisory Board of the League of the Red Cross Societies in Geneva, August 13, 1920
  - 20 members of the Medical Staff, League Red Cross Societies, Geneva, 1920
  - N.J. State Commission on Alcoholic Beverage Control Legislation, nine unidentified members, 1933
  - "To the White Swan Inn", ancestral home of Franklin Paine Mall built in 1779, n.d.
  - William Henry Welch and group of men from F.H. Garrison, Welch Medical Library, Baltimore
  - William Henry Welch, standing with "Susan and Archie", 1887
    On Back: Memorandum by Mr. Dakin: At Charlton Hall, Irvington, summer of 1887. Susan and Archie with Doctor Welch, looking at rabbits being used for poliomyelitis experimental work
  - William Henry Welch, seated at desk, ca. 1910
  - William Henry Welch, September 1927
  - William Henry Welch with six unidentified men, n.d.
  - Harry M. [Thorias], seated at desk, ca. 1912
    Written on back: Harry [Henry] M. [Thorias] neurologist John Hopkins Medical School about 1912. Photo by Frederick T. Gates
  - The South African Institute for Medical Research, Laboratory No. 15, Vaccine Department, n.d.
  - The South African Institute for Medical Research, Laboratory No. 21, Bacteriological Research, n.d.
  - Five unidentifed individuals in the Library of the Rockefeller Institute
  - Simon Flexner sitting in the Pathological Lab, 1943
  - Simon Flexner leaning against bookcase, 1943
  - Portrait of Simon Flexner., n. d.; 1.0 p.; Half length portrait of Flexner, seated, microscope on table.
  - Simon Flexner, seated at desk with books., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length portrait of Flexner, seated at desk, hand on open book, book shelves in background.
  - Simon Flexner, seated, arms crossed., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half lenght portrait of Flexner, seated with arms crossed.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner as a young woman., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Bust length formal portrait of Helen Flexner.
    General note
    Photograph also included with others in APSimg7708.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner riding a donkey outside of the Ming Tombs, Peking., 1915; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Helen Flexner on donkey, man standing beside her.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner at the Ming Tombs, Peking., 1915; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length vie of Helen Flexner holding book.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner and Simon Flexner feeding the sacred deer at Kara, Japan., 1.0 Item(s); Two photographs, one of Helen and one of Simon, both in rickshaws, feeding deer.
  - Simon Flexner and Helen Thomas Flexner riding donkleys in Egypt., ca. 1924; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of the Flexners on camels, other men standing nearby.
  - "The Patriarch, besides Horus.", ca. 1924; 1.0 Item(s); Helen Thomas Flexner posing next to statue of Horus, in Egypt.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner gazing at statue of Horus, in Egypt., ca. 1924; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Helen Flexner, looking at Horus statue.
  - Simon Flexner, Helen Thomas Flexner, and unidentified man in Egypt., ca. 1924; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of the Flexners and unidentified man, standing near pyramids.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner at the Great Wall of China., 1915; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Helen Flexner, standing outside at Great Wall, mountains in background.
  - Four images of Helen Thomas Flexner from the Flexner Family Photo Album., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Four images of Helen Flexner, two full length, one seated, one bust length portrait.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner, four photographs., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Four photographs of Helen Flexner, two full length views, two portraits.
  - Helen Thomas Flexner, portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of Helen Flexner.
    Photograph also included with others in APSimg7709.
  - Dr. & Mrs. Flexner., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); View of Simon and Helen Flexner, seated outside, label from album page visible.
  - Simon Flexner and Helen Thomas Flexner aboard the S.S. Roma., 1.0 Item(s); Two photographs, one of Simon Flexner, one of Helen Flexner, both seated reading books.
  - Simon Flexner and Professor Neufeld, December 1927
  - Anatole France, 1920
  - Dr. Inada, n.d.
  - Robert Koch, n.d.
  - Simon Flexner and Frau Landan, March 16, 1934
  - Henry Fairfield Osborn, [ca. 1907]
  - Ivan Petrovich Pavlov, n.d.
  - Resident Dinner, Johns Hopkins Hospital, May 5, 1892
  - Dedication of the Institute of Pathology, Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, October 7, 1929
  - Simon Flexner and Hideyo Noguchi with a group at the Rockefeller Institute
  - Unidentifed group seated on steps at the Rockefeller Institute, n.d.
  - Morris Flexner, n.d.
  - Flexner Family, [ca. 1890]
  - Dr. and Mrs. Flexner at dinner, Japan, 1915
  - Simon Flexner and George Ellery Hale [?]
  - William Henry Welch, etched drawing, n.d.
  - Carl Voegtlin [?] half length frontal portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length, full frontal portrait of Voegtlin (?) with hand on table.
  - Children in playground, buildings in background., 1.0 Photograph(s); Children in various activities in a playground.
  - Claude Bernard formal portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal portrait of Claude Bernard, with bow tie and watch chain.
  - Dancing children in white dresses., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group of girls out doors in white dresses appear to be beginning a dance, while other children and adults look on.
  - Dr. H. Noguchi in a laboratory of the Rockefeller Institute, New York., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Postcard image of Noguchi in lab coat sitting at table near microscope and beakers.
  - Dr. K. Landsteiner, seated in lab coat., 1.0 Photograph(s); Candid profile portrait of Landsteiner in lab coat with collar raised.
  - Ester Abraham Flexner seated near small table., ca. 1860; 1.0 Item(s); Formal full length seated portait of Ester Flexner holding fan.
  - Group portrait of eighteen unidentified men and one dog., 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal group portrait of men, seated and standing, dog lying down.
  - Harvey Cushing at desk with lab coat., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Harvey Cushing with book at desk with portraits on wall.
  - Hideyo Noguchi holding beaker in laboratory., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Candid portrait of Noguch seated in laboratory.
  - James Wesley Jobling formal portrait, seated, n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal studio portrait, 3/4 view, with arm resting on back of chair.; Photograph is matted on thin board with simple border decorations, creating a relatively unadorned carte de visite.
  - Johannes Paulus Lotsy formal studio portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Card photograph, 3/4 view portrait of Lotsy with tie and coat.
  - Man standing on platform, holding hat., 1.0 Photograph(s); Unidentified man standing on concrete platform, a police officer and small crowd in background.
  - Marie Curie formal portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal 3/4 view portrait of Curie.
    Reverse has advertisement for the firm that created this carte de visite.
  - Martha Carey Thomas, profile, holding book., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length profile portrait of Thomas holding book.
  - Oscar H. and Emily Reinholt with their three children., 1922; 1.0 Photograph(s); Oscar and Emily Reinholt holding thier children, Dorothy, Margaret and Haldor Roald.
    Information concerning place and date of birth of each child attached to back of photograph.
  - Pierre Curie formal portrait with coat., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal 3/4 view studio portrait of Pierre Curie with beard.
    Reverse has advertisments for the French firm that made this carte de visite.
  - Shibasaburo Kitasato, formal portrait, seated., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal studio portrait of Kitasato, with white gloves and wearing a medal, top hat on nearby table.
    On reverse there are advertisements of the studio that made this carte de visite in both Japanese and English.
  - Theophil Mitchell Prudden seated holding hat., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of Prudden sitting on wooded chair, holding hat.
  - Three men standing in laboratory at Rockefeller Institute., 1.0 Photograph(s); Three men stand with arms folded in laboratory, with shelves of beakers behind them.
  - Unidentified man, formal 3/4 view portrait, seated., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 view formal portrait of man with circular glasses and tuxedo, with hands in lap.
  - Florence Sabin, formal portrait, seated., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of Sabin seated in chair.